Now there are lots of different ways to give advice.
现在有很多不同的方式来提供建议。
We've talked about some ways to ask for advice.
我们已经讨论了一些寻求建议的方法。
There are many many more ways to give advice.
提供建议的方式还有很多。
So let's go over some of the common phrases we can use to do it and we'll start with a really really
所以让我们回顾一下我们可以用来做这件事的一些常用短语，我们将从一个真正的
basic stuff.
基本的东西。
And I'm guessing that you probably already know most of these.
我猜你可能已经知道其中的大部分。
So you can you can it is is soft so we'll talk about different levels of strength.
所以你可以你可以它是柔软的，所以我们将讨论不同水平的力量。
If you say you could or you can.
如果你说你可以或者你可以。
Sometimes we use could to recommend what people do.
有时我们用 can 来推荐人们做什么。
It's like we're putting it up there.
就像我们把它放在那里一样。
But if the other person doesn't follow it it's OK it's OK so you can try and maybe running three days
但是如果其他人不遵循它没关系没关系，所以你可以尝试，也许运行三天
a week if you want to lose weight.
如果你想减肥，一周。
You could try running four or five days a week if you want to lose weight.
如果你想减肥，你可以尝试每周跑步四五天。
OK that is a suggestion for what to do.
好的，这是一个关于做什么的建议。
That's advice but it's very soft.
这是建议，但它非常软。
That means it's not too pushy not too pushy.
这意味着它不是太咄咄逼人，也不是太咄咄逼人。
Whereas if you say you should.
而如果你说你应该。
That is much more pushy much pushy here.
这在这里更加咄咄逼人。
OK you should.
好的，你应该。
It's almost as though if you don't do that I will be personally disappointed.
就好像你不这样做，我个人会感到失望。
This is how should is often used.
这是应该经常使用的方式。
So these two basically are the same.
所以这两个基本上是一样的。
It's just that the feeling is different that the level of pushing this is different.
只是感觉不一样，推动这个的层次不一样。
The strength is different.
强度不一样。
Now we can also recommend using questions and these are both pretty common.
现在我们也可以推荐使用问题，这些都很常见。
Why don't you Why don't you just quit.
你为什么不你为什么不干脆放弃。
Why don't you just quit.
你为什么不干脆放弃。
It's a question though.
虽然这是一个问题。
So if you're having a difficult time at your job.
因此，如果您在工作中遇到困难。
My bad boss whatever.
我的坏老板无论如何。
Why don't you just quit and get a new job.
你为什么不干脆辞职找一份新工作。
That's very common advice.
这是非常普遍的建议。
And maybe that's the best advice.
也许这是最好的建议。
I'm not recommending you do that if you don't like your job.
如果你不喜欢你的工作，我不建议你这样做。
I don't know the whole situation OK.
我不知道整个情况OK。
Or we could say how about How about you just quit.
或者我们可以说你刚刚退出怎么样。
How about you just quit.
你干脆辞职怎么样。
How about How about just breaking up with him or her or if you're with a girlfriend or boyfriend who
和他或她分手怎么样，或者如果你和一个女朋友或男朋友在一起怎么样？
is not the right fit for you and you're depressed or unhappy for whatever reason then your friend might
不适合您，并且无论出于何种原因您感到沮丧或不开心，那么您的朋友可能会
give you that advice.
给你这个建议。
How about or why don't you pretty much the same.
怎么样或为什么不你几乎一样。
How about why don't you just break up with him just break up with her.
你为什么不和他分手就和她分手吧。
You're not the right match.
你不是合适的人选。
That's OK.
没关系。
Move on.
继续前行。
Move on move on.
继续前进。
You can use that for the job situation or the girlfriend boyfriend situation.
您可以将其用于工作情况或女朋友男朋友的情况。
Maybe it's time to move on.
也许是时候继续前进了。
That means to take the next step in your life either for work or for personal stuff.
这意味着要为工作或个人事物迈出人生的下一步。
It can be used in lots of different lots of different situations.
它可以用于许多不同的情况。
OK.
好的。
So these are all really common using questions to give advice or using these simple phrases you can
所以这些都是很常见的使用问题来提供建议或使用这些简单的短语你可以
you should.
你应该。
I left out.
我漏掉了。
So you've probably seen you ought to in American English.
所以你可能已经看到你应该用美式英语。
It's just not that common anymore.
只是不再那么常见了。
People don't use it that often.
人们不经常使用它。
So you could use that ought to.
所以你应该使用它。
But I think it's more common to say you can you could and you should.
但我认为更常见的说法是你可以，你应该。
Much more common.
更常见。
Now we get into some ways to give advice which are a little bit more complicated than the ones we just
现在我们进入一些方法来提供建议，这些方法比我们刚才的方法要复杂一些
talked about.
讨论过。
So let's go through them one by one and I'll explain how we can use each of them.
因此，让我们一一浏览它们，我将解释我们如何使用它们。
OK.
好的。
Now this is a very common style of expression in English anyway were and would always remember that
现在，无论如何，这是一种非常常见的英语表达方式，并且会永远记住
were and would usually go together to create something that's not real.
曾经并且通常会一起创造一些不真实的东西。
And we've talked about that before.
我们之前已经讨论过这个问题。
It's a hypothetical hypothetical very small hypothetical is something that we imagine OK.
这是一个假设的假设 非常小的假设是我们认为可以的。
If I were you I would.
如果我是你我会。
It's a very useful way to give advice because we're putting our selves in the shoes of the person we're
这是提供建议的一种非常有用的方式，因为我们将自己设身处地为我们自己的人着想
giving advice to to show them that we empathize with them.
提供建议以向他们展示我们对他们的同情。
So when we empathize when we empathize we show the other person that we understand their situation.
因此，当我们产生同理心时，我们会向对方表明我们了解他们的处境。
We can say put yourself in my shoes or I will put myself in your shoes or in her shoes in his shoes.
我们可以说设身处地为我着想，或者我会设身处地为你设身处地，或者设身处地为他设身处地。
Try to understand their situation.
尝试了解他们的情况。
So this is a really useful one because it shows that if I were you I would just move on.
所以这是一个非常有用的，因为它表明如果我是你，我会继续前进。
Maybe it's time to quit and find a new job.
也许是时候辞职并找到一份新工作了。
If I were you I would just move on.
如果我是你，我会继续前进。
This is probably my favorite way and one of the most common ways to give advice.
这可能是我最喜欢的方式，也是最常见的提供建议的方式之一。
OK.
好的。
We can also use wood in this way.
我们也可以通过这种方式使用木材。
I would wood just to make it softer.
我会用木头让它更柔软。
You couldn't just say I suggest that you could say.
你不能只说我建议你可以说。
I would suggest that you just find a new job.
我建议你找一份新工作。
Take your career to the next level.
将您的职业生涯提升到一个新的水平。
Move on.
继续前行。
I would suggest that you move on and we use wood to make it a little soft it just doesn't really have
我建议你继续前进，我们用木头让它有点软，它真的没有
a very very clear meaning or use in the sentence but it does make it a little bit more indirect and
句子中非常明确的含义或用法，但确实使它更加间接和
it kind of takes some of the focus off what we're saying.
它有点分散了我们所说的注意力。
We often use just in that way.
我们经常这样使用。
Oh just three miles.
哦，只有三英里。
How far did you run.
你跑了多远。
Just five miles to try to take some focus off of how many miles that is to try to make it seem like
只需五英里，就可以将注意力从试图让它看起来像多少英里上转移开
it's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
OK.
好的。
This is also very common.
这也很常见。
Another way we can show empathy or empathize with the person who's asking us for advice is to use whenever
我们可以向向我们寻求建议的人表示同情或同情的另一种方式是在任何时候使用
I.
我。
And then share a story about something that you experienced in the past which is very similar or exactly
然后分享一个你过去经历过的非常相似或完全相同的故事
the same.
相同。
So let's say someone is asking for advice because they feel homesick.
因此，假设有人因为想家而寻求建议。
You know you're in college and your roommate is always talking about oh I miss my mom I miss my dad
你知道你在上大学，你的室友总是在谈论哦，我想念我的妈妈，我想念我的爸爸
it's terrible I'm so homesick.
太可怕了，我很想家。
They miss their home.
他们想念他们的家。
That's what homesick means.
这就是想家的意思。
Whenever I feel homesick I just go out with some friends have a cup of coffee.
每当我想家的时候，我就和几个朋友出去喝杯咖啡。
Have a great conversation and it helps to distract me from how I feel.
进行一次精彩的交谈，这有助于分散我的注意力。
Try that whenever I feel homesick.
每当我想家时就试试。
I always.
我总是。
So then we say what we do.
所以我们说我们做什么。
Whenever I feel homesick I usually give my parents a call.
每当我想家时，我通常都会给父母打电话。
Call them on the phone.
打电话给他们。
Talk to them for a while.
和他们聊一会儿。
Whenever I feel homesick I may just take a quick trip home for the weekend and then come back.
每当我想家时，我可能会快速回家过周末，然后再回来。
Always feeling much much better.
总感觉好多了。
So we're trying to use our own experience to help other people which is a very obviously good way to
所以我们正在尝试利用我们自己的经验来帮助其他人，这显然是一个很好的方式
share advice because you can show them that it works hey it worked for me.
分享建议，因为您可以向他们展示它有效，嘿它对我有用。
It's probably going to work for you too.
它可能也对你有用。
It works.
有用。
Something works that means it's successful.
有些东西有效，这意味着它是成功的。
It's effective.
这是有效的。
And because you're sharing that real example you're showing that it's effective.
因为你分享了这个真实的例子，所以你证明它是有效的。
You're not just throwing out some idea using your own life experience.
你不只是用你自己的生活经验抛出一些想法。
OK now sometimes we want to give two pieces of advice or two bits of advice at the same time and that's
好的，现在有时我们想同时给出两条建议或两条建议，那就是
a really good thing because sometimes there's obvious advice there's obvious advice and we'll talk more
一件非常好的事情，因为有时有明显的建议有明显的建议，我们会多谈
about that word in a second if something is obvious.
如果有什么是显而易见的，请在一秒钟内了解该词。
You probably already know that right.
你可能已经知道了。
Probably already know you can call your parents probably.
可能已经知道你可能会打电话给你的父母。
OK.
好的。
That's pretty obvious.
这很明显。
So you can give two different bits in a row and that might help you move the conversation forward a
因此，您可以连续给出两个不同的位，这可能会帮助您将对话向前推进
little more quickly first.
先快一点。
You can give your parents a call and if that doesn't work that means if giving your parents a call is
你可以给你父母打电话，如果这不起作用，这意味着如果给你父母打电话是
not successful not successful the next step would be for you to for example face time them or do a video
不成功 不成功 下一步是让您与他们面对面交流或制作视频
call or hang out with friends more or go home for a visit.
打电话或多和朋友一起出去玩，或者回家探访。
OK.
好的。
First you can call your parents and if that doesn't work drive home or take the bus home visit them
首先你可以打电话给你的父母，如果这不起作用，开车回家或乘公共汽车回家探望他们
for a weekend and then come back you will feel better to bits.
一个周末再回来你会感觉好多了。
That's very good.
这是非常好的。
The next one is also to get rid of the obvious the obvious bit of advice.
下一个也是摆脱明显的建议。
The obvious piece of advice so that you can go to the real stuff because it's so obvious that you should
显而易见的建议，这样你就可以去真正的东西，因为它是如此明显，你应该
call your parents if you haven't tried that yet.
如果您还没有尝试过，请致电您的父母。
Maybe you're not the smartest tool in the shed.
也许你不是棚子里最聪明的工具。
So have you ever.
你也有过。
Wait I can take this out.
等我把这个拿出来。
All right.
好的。
Have you ever tried.
你尝试过吗。
We can use this in some situations but for the home sickness one it doesn't quite work.
我们可以在某些情况下使用它，但对于家庭病来说，它并不完全有效。
I feel so homesick.
我好想家。
What should I do.
我应该怎么办。
I really need some advice.
我真的需要一些建议。
Could you give me some advice.
你能给我一些建议吗？
Have you tried calling your parents.
你有没有试过打电话给你的父母。
Yeah I tried that.
是的，我试过了。
OK well now you can and then you can give more advice.
好吧，现在你可以了，然后你可以提供更多建议。
Oh if you already tried that you already did that go home for the weekend visit.
哦，如果您已经尝试过，那么您已经这样做了，回家过周末。
Or maybe get on Facebook and check some old photos or chat with them online.
或者，也许上 Facebook 并查看一些旧照片或在线与他们聊天。
Whatever advice you want to give.
无论你想给出什么建议。
Now when can we use.
现在什么时候可以使用。
I had ever here before.
我以前来过这里。
When can we use ever.
我们什么时候可以使用。
Have you ever tried that.
你有没有试过。
This would be for a much larger thing that we're giving advice about.
这将是我们提供建议的更大的事情。
So I've maybe tried to quit smoking many many times and failed.
所以我可能多次尝试戒烟，但都失败了。
I'm trying again.
我再试一次。
Well have you ever.
你有没有过。
Have you ever tried using one of those patches little patch people put on their arms to quit smoking.
您是否曾经尝试过使用人们戴在手臂上的那些小贴片来戒烟。
Have you ever tried using one of those patches to ever kind of focuses on something that is a larger
你有没有尝试过使用其中一个补丁来专注于更大的东西
scale in your whole life.
在你的一生中规模化。
Have you tried this.
你有没有试过这个。
That's when we usually use ever.
那是我们通常使用的时候。
Have you ever done that.
你有没有这样做过。
Have you ever been to Canada.
你去过加拿大吗。
Have you ever tried using those patches so it would be for that kind of advice which is something that
你有没有试过使用这些补丁，所以它会是那种建议
maybe happens over a lifetime or over several years.
可能会在一生或几年内发生。
The homesick example is kind of a right now type of advice.
想家的例子是一种现在的建议。
OK so these are all really common ways these are a little bit more complicated but they're also a little
好的，所以这些都是非常常见的方式有点复杂，但它们也有点
bit more specific and I think they're very very effective ways to give advice.
更具体一点，我认为它们是提供建议的非常有效的方法。
And if you're using the first two whenever I and I would suggest and if I were you able to show the
如果你在我和我建议的时候使用前两个，如果我能够展示
other person that you actually care about them.
其他你真正关心他们的人。